Guide to the Gerald Robert Vizenor Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Gerald Robert Vizenor papers
1880-2015
1960-2015
YCAL MSS 539
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
69.86
(99 boxes) + 1 cold storage and 2 broadside
The collection consists of writings, correspondence, research and teaching material, photographs, printed material, audiovisual material, computer disks, and other papers, documenting the literary and academic career of Gerald Robert Vizenor and relating to many of his published works on Native American literature, history, and culture.
Vizenor, Gerald Robert, 1934-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Ken Lopez Bookseller on various funds, 2000-2015. For more information consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 44 and 102 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 45, 47 (reel-to-reel recording, video and film reels): Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Boxes 46, 80, 85, 101 (digital media): Restricted Fragile. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Gerald Robert Vizenor (1934)
Gerald Robert Vizenor is a Native American author, poet, and teacher. His works of prose comprise both fiction and nonfiction, and include The People Named the Chippewa: Narrative Histories (1984), Bearheart: The Heirship Chronicles (1990; originally published as Darkness in Saint Louis Bearheart in 1978), The Heirs of Columbus (1991), and Manifest Manners: Postindian Warriors of Survivance (1994), among others. Vizenor is the founder and editor of the American Indian Literature and Critical Studies series at the University of Oklahoma Press.
Vizenor was born in 1934, and is an enrolled member of the Minnesota Chippewa Tribe, White Earth Reservation. He graduated from the University of Minnesota in 1960, and is Professor of American Studies at the University of New Mexico, and Professor Emeritus at the University of California, Berkeley.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of writings, correspondence, research and teaching material, photographs, printed material, audiovisual material, computer disks, and other papers, documenting the literary and academic career of Gerald Robert Vizenor and relating to many of his published works on Native American literature, history, and culture.
Arrangement
Organized into five groupings: August 2000 Acquisition; August 2004 Acquisition; May 2008 Acquisition; October 2012 Acquisition; September 2015 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time.
Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with and/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, correspondence and writings can be found in all three groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Researchers should also note that similar material can be arranged differently in each acquisition, depending on how the material was organized when it was received by the library.
American fiction -- Indian authors; American literature -- Indian authors; American poetry -- Indian authors; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Indian literature -- United States; Indians of North America -- Fiction; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiocassettes; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Electronic documents; Motion pictures (visual works); Photographs; Sound recordings; Videocassettes; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Vizenor, Gerald Robert, 1934-
- August 2000 Acquisition, 1880-2000; 1960-2000; 69.86; (99 boxes) + 1 cold storage, 2 broadside
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Ken Lopez Bookseller on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 2000.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 44 (audio and video cassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 45, 47 (reel-to-reel recording, video and film reels): Restricted Fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 46 (computer disks): Restricted Fragile. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  General note
  Formerly classed as Uncat MSS 71.
  - Stone Columbus: The Heirs of Christopher Columbus, notes and draft, 1990 Nov (Box 1)
  - Wordarrows, first complete typescript, 1977 Aug (Box 1)
  - Postindian Conversations
    - Corrected typescript, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Corrected bound page proof, 1999 Apr 10 (Box 1)
    - Typescript in blue-green binder, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Maroon Crazy Papers, Ronin Bloom, Telegraph Novella, unpublished ideas for stories, 1982-1985, undated (Box 1)
  - Terminal Creeds, Ideas for Stories, 1975-1985, undated (Box 1)
  - The Moccasin Games, typescript, undated (Box 1)
  - Interview with Gerald Vizenor, Santa Fe, 1985 Dec 19 (Box 1)
  - Counting Coup at the Movies, University of California Press, book proposal, [1980?] (Box 1)
  - University of Minnesota Press, Book Outlines for Ghost Dance Socks and The Anishinaabe (unpublished), 1980 (Box 1)
  - Santa Maria Casino, unpublished screenplay, undated (Box 1)
  - Minnesota Historical Society, proposal and essay (unpublished), 1986 (Box 1)
  - Hoxie Film Project (unproduced), 1988-1990 (Box 1)
  - "Fineday Off St. Timothy's Rock", 1966 Jul 22 (Box 2)
  - Four Skin, notes, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Mixedblood Earth Divers, story ideas, 1974-1978 (Box 2)
  - Story Ideas, Names-Outlines, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Early unpublished poems, 1955-1980 (Box 2)
  - Fate in August, unpublished novel, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Four Skins, typescripts with corrections, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Heirs of Columbus
    - First draft, manuscript, undated (Box 3)
    - First draft, typescript in red binder, undated (Box 3)
    - Page proofs, 1991 (Box 3)
  - USIA trips, correspondence, 1991 (Box 3)
  - University of Oklahoma Press Literature Series, correspondence, 1991 Jan 22 (Box 3)
  - Harold of Orange
    - Screenplay, early draft, undated (Box 3)
    - "A Non-Indian Viewer's Guide to Gerald Vizenor's Harold of Orange", 1986 Fall (Box 3)
    - Sundance Institute articles and literature regarding Harold of Orange, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Screenplay with newspaper clippings, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Press release and newspaper clippings, undated (Box 3)
    - New York Times Magazine with article on Sundance in the year of Harold of Orange, 1983 Oct 23 (Box 3)
  - Minnesota Historical Society, Mss Collection, correspondence, 1975-1983 (Box 3)
  - Crossbloods
    - Crossbloods, final copy-edited manuscript, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Bound page-proofs, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Notes, with newspaper clippings, 1982-1989, undated (Box 3)
  - Heirs of Columbus
    - Holograph manuscript drafts and first typescript draft, undated; 3 (Box 4)
    - Bound typescript, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Notes, labeled "Columbus 1990-1992" (Box 4)
    - Notes and drafts, undated (Box 4)
  - Darkness in St. Louis Bearheart
    - Bearheart, finances, 1978-1986 (Box 5)
    - Draft of section with corrections, undated (Box 5)
    - Printed version, marked copy, 1978 (Box 5)
    - Bearheart: The Heirship Chronicles, typescript, undated; 2 (Box 5)
    - First typescript draft, undated (Box 5)
    - Publishing agreements, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Manifest Manners
    - Typescript of introduction, with letter from University of Nebraska Press, 1999 Jun 4 (Box 5)
    - Drafts for introduction, 1999 Feb 5 (Box 5)
    - Notes, bound typescript, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Typescript, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Notes for Manifest Manners and an unpublished play, undated; 2 (Box 5)
    - Cover photo, typescript for title page and introduction, 1999 (Box 5)
    - Typescript introduction, with substitution and letter to University of Nebraska Press, 1999 Jun 9 (Box 5)
    - Bound typescript, undated (Box 5)
  - Crossbloods, research materials, marked copy of printed version, 1964-1990 (Box 5)
  - Thomas James White Hawk
    - Transcript of James White Hawk sentence commutation hearing, 1969 Jan 17; 2 (Box 6)
    - Research material, 1967-1969; 8 (Box 6)
    - Notebook with notes on White Hawk case, undated (Box 6)
    - Photographs, mostly unidentified, [1960s]; 10 (Box 7)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes some in boxes labeled "The Everlasting Sky" and some of James White Hawk and one of Sen. and Mrs. Hubert Humphrey "playing Indian"; one page of notes on White Hawk case.
    - Negatives (Box 7)
    - Transcript of James White Hawk sentence commutation hearing, 1969 Jan 17; 2 (Box 7)
    - Notes, press releases, newspaper clippings on White Hawk case, including Vizenor's book on the case, 1967-1969 (Box 7)
    - Transcripts of South Dakota vs. William Winford Stands trial, 1967 Dec 6; 3 (Box 8)
    - Photographs, photocopies of newspaper clippings on White Hawk case and efforts to abolish capital punishment, 1967-1968 (Box 8)
    - Notes, typescripts from White Hawk case, 1968 (Box 8)
    - White Hawk case notes and typescripts, 1969 (Box 8)
    - Memoranda on White Hawk case and others, 1969 (Box 8)
    - Newspaper clippings, notes on White Hawk case, 1968-69 (Box 8)
    - Material on White Hawk case (Box 8)
    - Transcript of White Hawk preliminary hearing, 1967 Mar 30 (Box 9)
    - Transcript of motion to suppress motion for change of venue in White Hawk case, 1967 Oct 27 (Box 9)
    - Transcript of White Hawk pre-sentence hearing, 1967 Nov 16 (Box 9)
    - Transcript of White Hawk post-conviction relief hearing, 1969 May 12; 2 (Box 9)
    - Transcript of depositions in White Hawk case, 1969 Mar 21 (Box 9)
    - Transcript of court proceedings, 1969 Apr 18 (Box 9)
    - Transcript of South Dakota vs. William Winford Stands, 1967 Dec 6 (Box 9)
    - Newspapers and clippings on White Hawk, 1968-1969; 3 (Box 9)
    - Four Winds, Letters on White Hawk, 1968-1969 (Box 9)
    - Letters, mostly to and from Vizenor or Delmara Harrison, 1967-1969 (Box 9)
    - Thomas James White Hawk, printed version [3 copies], 1968 (Box 9)
    - Notes and other material on White Hawk case, 1967-1969 (Box 9)
    - Transcript of NBC's First Tuesday featuring a report on White Hawk [2 copies], 1969 Dec 2 (Box 9)
    - Photographs, [1968] (Box 9)
    - Notebooks from White Hawk and Stands trials; mental disorders manual, 1965-1969 (Box 9)
  - "Valentine for Leonard Peltier," poster
  - UC-Santa Cruz newspapers, flyers, memos, etc., 1989-1990 (Box 10)
  - Interior Landscapes and Crossbloods
    - Photograph copies, undated (Box 10)
    - Original artwork, 1989-1990 (Box 10)
  - Four Books - Minnesota (Box 10)
  - Wesleyan University Press, correspondence, 1990-1999 (Box 10)
  - Reviews and publications of or by Vizenor, 1977-1989; 9 (Box 10)
    Includes Elisabeth Simonot, Trickster et Sang-Croise dans Trois Nouvelles de Gerald Vizenor (dissertation with letter to GV in English), "Water Striders (Haiku Poems)," and poetry pamphlet by Vizenor labeled "scarce," among other material.
  - Reviews and publications of or by Vizenor (Box 11)
  - Photographs, mostly from Sundance, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Narrative Chance Conference, Santa Cruz, 1988-1989 (Box 11)
  - Native American Literature Prize, press releases and correspondence, 1991-1996 (Box 11)
  - Personnel Committee, UC-Santa Cruz, 1988-1989 (Box 11)
  - UC-Santa Cruz class evaluations, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Indians and Jews, Spring 1996, syllabus (Box 11)
  - Graduate seminar, syllabus, 1995 (Box 11)
  - Search review, 1994-1995 (Box 11)
  - Berkeley research seminar, schedules, student information, correspondence, 1996-1998 (Box 11)
  - Photographs of Vizenor from Faces of Berkeley series, with cover letter, 1996 Feb 16 (Box 11)
  - Photograph of Vizenor from Michelle Vignes, with cover letter, 1992 Sep 14 (Box 11)
  - Photographs of Vizenor, no letter, 1997 Dec 2 (Box 11)
  - Shadow Distance, bound typescript, corrected, undated (Box 11)
  - Native American Literature, bound proof, undated (Box 11)
  - "Heartlines," short story, typescript corrected, undated (Box 11)
  - "The Elevator Shaman," short story, typescript and corrected proofs, 1998-1999 (Box 11)
  - "The Psychotaxidermist," in The Minneapolis Star
  - Research on Russell Means, 1991-1992 (Box 11)
  - Event brochures, reviews, other ephemera, 1995-2000 (Box 11)
  - Native American Indian History Month, University of Illinois, poster
  - Jack Foley interview with Vizenor, 1996 Aug 26 (Box 11)
  - "Trickster Discourse," essay, printed version in American Indian Quarterly, 1990 Summer (Box 11)
  - Program from Library Laureates Dinner 2000, 2000 Apr 10 (Box 11)
  - Newspaper articles, reviews, flyers, 1977-1997 (Box 11)
  - Academic review, 1996 (Box 11)
  - Academic review, 1998 (Box 12)
  - Autobiographical essays, 1995 (Box 12)
  - Ishi and the Wood Ducks, screenplay, 1995 Mar (Box 12)
  - Short stories, photocopies, 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - Critical essays, photocopies, 1993-1995 (Box 12)
  - Literary interviews, photocopies, 1994 (Box 12)
  - Course material, UC Berkeley, 1994-1996 (Box 12)
  - Book reviews of and by Vizenor, 1993-1994 (Box 12)
  - Academic reviews, 1992-1999; 3 (Box 13)
  - Third World Conference program, 1996 Mar 27-30 (Box 13)
  - Jonathan Boyarin, "Storm from Paradise," including essay about Vizenor, 1992 June (Box 13)
  - Framing the Questions, including articles about Vizenor, 2000 (Box 13)
  - Elaine Jahner, "Heading 'Em Off at the Impasse," article on Indian authors with mentions of Vizenor, undated (Box 13)
  - Kimberly M. Blaeser, "Gerald Vizenor: Writing - in the Oral Tradition," PhD dissertation, 1989 Nov (Box 13)
  - "One" by Sol Krueger, sheet music, bound (inspired by Vizenor's "Seventeen Chirps")
  - Report on American Indian Employment Center of Minneapolis, set up by Vizenor in 1966, 1967 Apr (Box 13)
  - MacArthur Foundation, 1993-1999 (Box 13)
  - Court documents from Clyde Bellecourt case, 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - "Saint Columban of White Earth," short story, 1984 Aug (Box 13)
  - "Luminous Thighs" and "Monsignor Missalwait," short stories, 1984-1985 (Box 13)
  - Plaque inscribed to Vizenor as "Acting Martyr" of UC Santa Cruz, 1990 Jul 2 (Box 13)
  - Landfill Meditations
    - Page proofs, 1991 Jun 13 (Box 13)
    - Typescripts, 1988-1990 (Box 13)
    - Bound typescript, 1991 (Box 13)
  - Student Strike, UC Berkeley, 1999 (Box 14)
  - Ethnic Studies, 1995-2000 (Box 14)
  - Native American Studies (Box 14)
  - Macalester College, correspondence and articles regarding Vizenor's honorary degree, 1999 (Box 14)
  - Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act, letters (Box 14)
  - Visionary Sovereignty, book proposal and correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 14)
  - Announcements, reviews, articles, 1994; 12 (Box 14)
  - Student papers on The Heirs of Columbus, with a syllabus and letter to Vizenor from the professor, 1992-1993 (Box 14)
  - Harper Collins, Literary Mosaics, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Fugitive Poses, Nebraska, 1997-2000 (Box 14)
  - Postindian Conversations, A. Robert Lee, University of Nebraska Press, 1998-2000 (Box 14)
  - Manifest Manners, 1993-2000; 2 (Box 15)
  - Interviews with Vizenor, 1987-1993; 2 (Box 15)
  - "The Stone Babies," story, typescript, undated (Box 15)
  - Manifest Manners, notes, undated (Box 15)
  - "Trickster Discourse," speech, typescript, 1990 Nov 30 (Box 15)
  - "The Envoy to Haiku," essay, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 15)
  - "The Ruins of Representation," typescripts, corrected, 1992 (Box 15)
  - Manifest Manners and Dead Voices, notes, undated (Box 15)
  - "Christopher Columbus: Lost Havens in the Ruins of Representation", undated (Box 15)
  - Memo regarding proposed furniture plant, 1969 Feb 26 (Box 15)
  - Essays, typescripts, 1984, undated; 2 (Box 15)
  - "Bone Courts," typescript, undated (Box 15)
  - "Naanabozho Curiosa," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 15)
  - Native American Indian Literature, bound typescript, corrected, 1994 May (Box 15)
  - Autobiographical essay, typescript and page proofs, with cover letter, 1995 July 27 (Box 15)
  - "Stone Columbus," typescript, with notes, undated (Box 15)
  - "Summer in the Spring", 1992 May 18 (Box 15)
  - Family correspondence, including letters to mother with a copy of her poetry book (Box 15)
  - Correspondence from LaVerne Harsch and other material, 1971-1990 (Box 15)
    Includes 3 computer disks
    Computer disks are restricted. Reference copies of electronic files are available through Access Services:
    Disk #20000822-y.0002, #20000822-y.0003; CD, "The Native American Experience"
    Disk #20000822-y.0004; CD, "Culture & History of the White Earth Ojibwe"
  - Raising the Moon Vines, bound proofs, with Vizenor letter to publisher, 1999 Apr 12; 2 (Box 15)
  - Cranes Arise (published version of Water Striders), bound proofs, 1999; 2 (Box 15)
  - Water Striders, bound proof, 1997 (Box 15)
  - Water Striders, typescript, corrected, 1997 (Box 15)
  - Transcript of interview with Nancy Bunge, undated (Box 16)
  - Stone Columbus (unpublished play), notes and correspondence, 1992 (Box 16)
  - Santa Maria Casino (Box 16)
  - Writings on Vizenor, undated; 4 (Box 16)
  - Photographs, "People Named the Chippewa", 1890s-1960s (Box 16)
  - The People Named the Chippewa, research material, 1980 (Box 16)
  - Family genealogy materials, 1880s-1970s (Box 16)
  - Awards, 1990-1996 (Box 16)
  - Greater Works magazine, including Vizenor article "Almost a Beauty Mark", 1968 Aug (Box 16)
  - Russian periodical, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Literary and Cultural Studies, including a review of The People Named the Chippewa, 1985 (Box 16)
  - University of Minnesota Press, catalogs, 1978, 1990 (Box 16)
  - Native Peoples, including article by Vizenor, 1993 Spring (Box 16)
  - Northeast Indian Quarterly, including an excerpt from The Stone Trickster, 1991 Fall (Box 16)
  - Sampler from Buried Roots and Indestructible Seeds, including text of Vizenor's Black River Falls speech, 1992 Oct (Box 16)
  - News from Native California, including an article co-written by Vizenor, 1993 Summer (Box 16)
  - Before Columbus Review, including an essay by Vizenor, 1989 Fall (Box 16)
  - San Francisco Review, including an interview with Vizenor, 1990 Winter (Box 16)
  - Ivory Tower Minnesota daily, 1962 Oct 15 (Box 16)
  - American Book Awards catalog, including a review of Griever, 1988 (Box 16)
  - University of Nebraska Press catalog, including a review of Fugitive Poses, 1998 Spring (Box 16)
  - The American Indian Quarterly, 1984 Fall; 2 (Box 17)
  - Zyzzyva, 1992 Winter (Box 17)
  - Dacotah Territory, including four Vizenor poems, 1973 Winter (Box 17)
  - Genre, including a review of Luminous Thighs, 1985 Summer (Box 17)
  - Halcyon, including an article by Vizenor, 1990 (Box 17)
  - World Literature Today, including excerpt from Dead Voices, 1992 Spring (Box 17)
  - Exposure, including article by Vizenor, 1993 Fall (Box 17)
  - Fiction International, including an excerpt from The Heirs of Columbus, 1991 Fall (Box 17)
  - North Dakota Quarterly, including a short story by Vizenor, 1985 Spring (Box 17)
  - The Wicazo Sa Review, including "Trickster Discourse", 1989 Spring (Box 17)
  - "Minnesota Chippewa: Woodland Treaties to Tribal Bingo," from American Indian Quarterly, 1989 Winter (Box 17)
  - American Studies International, including mentions of Vizenor, 1986 Oct (Box 17)
  - Frogpond, including Vizenor contribution, 1988 Nov (Box 17)
  - Fiction Collective, featuring a review of Griever, 1987 Fall (Box 17)
  - Conference program from International Conference on American Literature, 1995 Mar 30 (Box 17)
  - University of Minnesota Press literary catalog, with form letter, 1988 Nov 30 (Box 17)
  - Studies in American Indian Literatures, including an article on Vizenor, 1997 Spring (Box 17)
  - Studies in American Indian Literatures, including a Vizenor bibliography and a letter to him, 1985 Jul 11 (Box 17)
  - Fugitive Poses, 5 (Box 17)
    Includes typescripts, corrected, master galleys, corrected, and bound final draft.
  - Fugitive Poses, 7 (Box 18)
  - Earthdivers, typescript, corrected, 1980 June (Box 18)
  - Published essays, typescripts, 1992-1999; 6 (Box 18)
  - Notes, undated (Box 18)
  - Haiku conference address and essays, 1999 Jul (Box 18)
  - Macalester College honorary degree speech, 1999 May 23 (Box 18)
  - Minneapolis Tribune article by Vizenor, "Shadow Work and Wage Labor," typescript, 1981 Dec 8 (Box 18)
  - Minneapolis Tribune articles by Vizenor, clippings and copies, 1968-1979, 1992
  - "Imagic Moments," first draft, typescript, 1999 Jan (Box 18)
  - Pieces from Visit Teepee Town, 1999 Jan (Box 18)
  - Lecture at Leeds University, 1996 Apr (Box 18)
  - Lecture at Bucknell University, "Earthdivers and Shadow Workers", 1981 Nov 12 (Box 18)
  - Literary Gambling Sticks, introduction, typescript, 1999 Feb 12 (Box 18)
  - Typescript of published interview, with cover letter to Vizenor, 1993 Jul 26 (Box 18)
  - "Matsushima, Pine Islands," bound typescript, 1983 (Box 19)
  - "Bone Rights," typescript, with relevant newspaper articles and letters, 1986 Aug (Box 19)
  - "The Mystic Warrior" (Vizenor's review of TV-Movie), typescript with articles on Indians in movies, 1984-1989 (Box 19)
  - Calvin Martin, Oxford Press Contract, with correspondence to/from Martin, 1982 (Box 19)
  - Summer Institute (founded and directed by Vizenor), 1999-2000; 7 (Box 19)
  - Myth, Imagination, and Language Games, Split Rock arts program, 1990 Aug (Box 19)
  - University of Oklahoma, 1990 May-Jul (Box 19)
  - CV-related, reviews, 1987-1990 (Box 19)
  - Vizenor's curriculum vitae, student reviews, various articles, 1988-1990 (Box 19)
  - Grant applications, correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 19)
  - Tianjin University, class papers and correspondence regarding Vizenor's year in residence, 1983-1984 (Box 19)
  - Curriculum vitae, letters of recommendation for University of Minnesota position, 1975-1984 (Box 19)
  - The Trickster of Liberty
    - Bound typescripts, 1986; 2 (Box 19)
    - Notes and typescript for original introduction, 1988 Feb (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, mostly from Vizenor, 1988 (Box 19)
  - Dead Voices
    - Draft, (1 computer disk)
      Computer disk is restricted. Reference copies of electronic files available through Access Services:
      Uncat MSS 41, Disk #1
    - Corrected proofs, 1991 May (Box 19)
    - Notes, 1990 (Box 19)
    - Bound typescript, 1991 May (Box 19)
    - Bound typescript (Box 20)
    - Typescript, with notes, illustrations, correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 20)
    - Notes for Dead Voices, undated (Box 20)
  - Bear Shadows (Box 20)
  - University of Nebraska Prose Award, 1989-1990 (Box 20)
  - James Welch, programs and correspondence on Oklahoma Native American Literature Prize recipient, 1991 (Box 20)
  - Plans for University of Nebraska nonfiction publication award, 1990 Feb 15 (Box 20)
  - N. Scott Momaday, Literature Prize, 1988-1989 (Box 20)
  - Kresge College provost and literary prize, 1988-1989 (Box 20)
  - Native American Literature Prize, UC Santa Cruz, 1988-1990 (Box 20)
  - Ethnic Studies, Berkeley Affiliation, 1987 (Box 20)
  - Inaugural lecture at UC-Santa Cruz, with cover letter, 1989 Feb 27 (Box 20)
  - Course evaluations, Santa Cruz, 1988 (Box 20)
  - Literature Board, correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 20)
  - Course requests, 1979-1990 (Box 20)
  - Promotion, UC Santa Cruz, 1987-1989 (Box 20)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1988 (Box 20)
  - Santa Cruz, Application review, with letters from other professors supporting Vizenor, 1986-1987 (Box 20)
  - Chancers
    - Typescript, 1999 Jun (Box 20)